A term you've seen already several times in this course and I promise you you're going to see it several
times more throughout the course.
Is Enterprise environmental factors.
So let's take a look at enterprise environmental factors and how they affect our projects.
Enterprise environmental factors can directly or indirectly influence how you manage the project directly
means you have to use this form you have to use this process indirectly.
Could be just the structure of the organization or the workflow or how you get people on and off your
team.
Project managers really have no control over Enterprise environmental factors.
We have no control over policies and procedures that you must do that's outside of the project enterprise
environmental factors can be things like rules and policies and regulations and laws.
Any time that you are required that you must do certain procedure your process you're likely dealing
with an enterprise environmental factor.
There are two types of enterprise environmental factors.
We have internal and external Let's talk about internal first internal enviro enterprise environmental
factors or e F's are created by the organization but outside of the project.
So you must use this particular piece of software.
You must have a communications report every Thursday.
You must follow this process for procurement.
So it's outside the project and its rules or policies that you have to follow.
Some examples here can also be organizational culture just the structure of the organization.
We'll talk a little bit more about the structure coming up because how your organization is structured
it will affect how much authority you have on the project.
So we'll take a little bit more look at that coming up.
Some other things here in this category things like leadership the vision the belief in the organization
the hierarchy of management ethics the organizational code of conduct expectations the physical location
of resources both physical and human resources.
These affect how you manage the project.
So if you need to get to a piece of equipment but it's in another state then you've got to coordinate
the logistics to get to that piece of equipment or to get materials on site.
And there's only so much room on site for the materials.
That's just the way it is it's an enterprise environmental factor and also people people can be distributed
we use virtual teams now they're non co-located but occasionally those people have to come into the
job site.
So you have travel and expenses and logistics there to consider the infrastructure of your organization.
So think about the I.T. infrastructure how you access data and printers how you log in the security.
Also the more that I as well the facilities or the equipment.
How do you check in and check out equipment.
Is there accountability for the equipment.
That's part of an internal E F some other things here that we have to think about I.T. software.
So we have software for scheduling that you have to use like Microsoft Project or base camp or Primavera.
So there's some things there that affect our approach configuration management.
How do you document and control the features and functions of the thing your project is creating.
So the product is an enterprise environmental factor as far as configuration management goes.
And then the work authorization system.
How do you approve work how do you schedule work especially if you're in a very complex matrix environment
which will see that coming up.
But you have people from all over the organizations so there's a lot more communication and a lot more
scheduling that would go into that scenario tied to that we have resource availability so people tools
equipment.
How do you obtain those resources.
You have to go through procurement yet to fill out a form.
You have to go talk to someone.
So it's just these layers of activities that you have to do.
But it's tied to accountability in your organization to get to the people the tools the facilities that
you need on your project.
And then we have employee capability just what's the capabilities of the people in the project.
So there may be some training that's needed some team development you may have to help people along
early in the project until they can get moving in and get going.
So those are all internal enterprise environmental factors.
What about external environmental factors external environment or factors are things outside of the
organization outside of your company.
So external are things like laws regulations market place conditions.
So you think about buying things and supply and demand and how that affects price or who you're allowed
to purchase from.
As far as laws in different countries and what type of security or encryption among different countries
that can affect your project you also have cultural influences and issues so think about the political
climate especially if you're in a government project customer perceptions of the technology or the solution
or your organization.
So that could affect how you manage the project.
And then things in the news especially if you're a large organization and you're doing a public type
project.
So what the news reports about your project or the Endeavor obviously that can affect your relationship
with the public and how you manage and do stakeholder engagement of course laws and regulations those
are always going to be external enterprise environmental factors.
And then a new idea here for you is a commercial database a commercial database as an organization can
purchase a piece of software a database and then that database will help predict duration or cost or
risk or benchmarking.
So for example years ago I was consulting in a printing company and we printed the lids to the top of
yogurt yogurt lids that you peel off the foil lid.
We printed the lids to that.
Well they had a piece of software where we would punch in the thickness of the foil is different thicknesses.
The number of colors used and then which printing press that was going to be printed on and it would
predict how many units or lids you could make per hour and how long it would take.
So that was a commercial database so you have these different factors you might have one of your industry
like in construction like cost per square foot or the type of square foot like the kitchen versus the
garage.
So how does that affect framing and timing.
So in your industry you might have a commercial estimating database or a commercial database and that's
an external wasn't created in your company but you use it to predict time and cost and risk management
and benchmarking some other external enterprise environmental factors your academic research.
So your organization may rely on white papers or studies from different universities and that helps
you to manage your project.
Government and industry standards that are unique to your discipline.
So I.T. health care insurance manufacturing.
So you have some standards now standard.
Is it necessary a law or regulation but it's a best practice like an industry standard financial organizations
that span multiple countries you've exchange exchange rates and tariffs and taxes and other things that
you have to consider on long projects we may have to take in consideration taxes.
So taxes at interest rates things like this.
I said taxes in particular really interest rate.
So if you're financing the project the cost of financing that is something we should consider and then
physical enterprise environmental factors the weather the environment where the project is physically
taking place.
Those are physical enterprise environmental factors.
All right.
So those are our enterprise environmental factors internal and external and we'll see that a few more
times throughout the course.
In fact we'll see an awful lot as we move through the course because that affects each process.
These can have some bearing on those.
All right.
Good job.